# Isabela Zeberio Aguerrevere

Ç isazeberio | in Isabela Zeberio Aguerrevere | ⊕ eudentify.eu | ≥ i.zeberioaguerrevere@uva.nl
Nationality: Venezuelan & Spanish

#### Summary

Social Scientist specializing in European Studies, identities, cultural evolution, and social interactions through computational methodology. Currently, I am a second-year PhD student at the University of Amsterdam, actively involved in the EUDENTIFY research project, which investigates the relationship between European Union institution building and European identity formation. With a background in Political Science and International Studies, I hold a Master's degree in Computational Social Science from the University Carlos III of Madrid.

# EDUCATION AND TRAINING

| 2023 - present | PhD Student at University of Amsterdam  |  |  |
|----------------|---|--|--|
|                | Thesis: European identity: Everyday notions of belonging                            |  |  |
|                | Advisors: Prof. Dr. Theresa Kuhn  |  |  |
| 2022 - 2023    | Master's Degree in Computational Social Science at University Carlos III (8.9/10.0) |  |  |
|                | Thesis: Conditional Effects of Media and Interpersonal Communication: An Agent-     |  |  |
|                | Based Approach to Opinion Formation on Brexit in London                             |  |  |
|                | Advisors: Prof. Dr. Iñaki Úcar, Prof. Dr. Theresa Kuhn                              |  |  |
| 2017 - 2022    | Bachelor's Degree in International Studies at University Carlos III (8.7/10.0)      |  |  |
|                | Thesis: Ballot Structure and Voter Turnout: The Case of Open Councils in Spain      |  |  |
|                | Advisor: Prof. Dr. Antonio Tena Junguito  |  |  |
| 2017 - 2022    | Bachelor's Degree in Political Science at University Carlos III (8.7/10.0)          |  |  |
|                | Thesis: Direct Democracy versus Representative: The Expenditure of Open Councils in |  |  |
|                | Spain   |  |  |
|                | Advisor: Prof. Dr. Ignacio Jurado   |  |  |
|                | 2021-2022 ERASMUS + Program at Université Catholique de Lille                       |  |  |
|                | 2020-2021 Non-European Mobility Program at Waterloo University                      |  |  |
| 2022           | Statistical Analysis with R at Fundación Carlos III                                 |  |  |

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Research Assistant at Weber State University

June 2021 - February 2022

- Assistant to Prof. Dr. Álvaro La Parra-Pérez.
- Study on the political and economic elites during the 20th century in Spain.
- Gathered primary source data on the boards of directors of major Spanish corporations from the Central Library of the Ministry of Finance and the National Library of Spain.
- Developed databases utilizing financial yearbooks of Spanish public limited companies.

### Research Assistant at Institución Milá I Fontanals (CSIC) January 2021 - December 2021

- Assistant to Dr. Débora Zurro Hernández.
- Contributed to the CaSEs-Culture and Socio-Ecological Dynamics Research Group's ARVCODA Project, focusing on evaluating the consumption of plant and marine resources across millennia.
- Compiled and organized databases using eHRAF World Cultures.
- Co-authored a publication titled "Los retos de la sostenibilidad y la investigación en Humanidades: las algas como recurso milenario", released in 2021 under Vitamina H(umanidades) IMF-CSIC.

- Assistant to Prof. Dr. Miguel Artola Blanco.
- Study on inequality in Spain, 1900-2000: markets, institutions and regulation.
- Developed databases documenting wages and taxes paid in Spain to facilitate in-depth analysis.
- Conducted meticulous transcription work on original sources preserved in the National Historical Archive and Villa Archive (Condeduque).
- Utilized data computation techniques to generate insightful graphs, aiding in the visualization and interpretation of research findings.

# SCHOLARSHIPS

| 2022-2023 E <sub>1</sub> | uropean Central | Bank Schol | larship for | · Women |
|--------------------------|-----------------|------------|-------------|---------|
|--------------------------|-----------------|------------|-------------|---------|

2022-2023 Tuition Grants for University Masters course UC3M (AM-01/22-23) (rejected)

2019 International Mobility Grant for Undergraduates UC3M (rejected)

2017-2023 Scholarships and Grants for Post-Compulsory Level Students -University Students (MECD)

## Conferences

Zeberio Aguerrevere, I. (2023, November 3). Conditional Effect of Media and Interpersonal Communication: An Agent-Based Approach to Opinion Formation on Brexit in London. ODISSEI Conference for Social Sciences in the Netherlands (OCSSN), Utrecht. Zenodo. <a href="https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10068798">https://doi.org/10.5281/zenodo.10068798</a>

# COMMUNITY SERVICE

2023 - present PhD Representative at the Amsterdam School for Regional, Transnational and European Studies (ARTES)

### LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue: Spanish

Other language(s):

|                        | Listening | Reading | Speaking | Writing |
|------------------------|-----------|---------|----------|---------|
| English                | C2        | C2      | C2       | C1      |
| French                 | B2        | B2      | B2       | B2      |
| $\operatorname{Dutch}$ | A1        | A1      | A1       | A1      |

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

# DIGITAL SKILLS

R | R Studio | Python | Microsoft Office | SQL | Git | Stata | GAML | LaTeX(Overleaf)